And just to convince you, I'm actually qualified to talk to you about this.
I should introduce myself.
My name is Ed Donner.
I'm the co-founder and CTO of an AI startup called Nebula.io.
You should go check him out.
I spent most of my career working for JP Morgan.
I started out in London, which is where I'm from originally.
I moved to Tokyo for a few months and then ended up in NYC, which is where I am right now.
And at the end of my time at J.P. Morgan, I was a managing director leading a team of about 300
technologists working in software engineering and Python and in analytics. And before my current
role at Nebula, I founded an AI startup called Untapped. And Untapped was acquired in 2021. And
this picture here is my magical moment, which is a billboard in Times Square announcing the acquisition of my startup.
And in case you don't believe me, you're like, eh, that could be any picture from Times Square.
I will tell you that if you if you squint and look very carefully, the thing I just circled in
green there is me. So there is evidence of this. I am, I am there on that billboard. And the other
reason I show this, not just to show off about my moment in Times Square,
but also because I actually live
like one block from Times Square.
It's very rare for people to live in this,
because it's such a sort of touristy area to be in,
but that is where I live, about a block that way,
behind that guitar.
If that guitar weren't there,
you would see my window that I'm looking out onto right now.
So that is where I am, if you can picture me right there making this.
And look, it's customary in these things
to show like a hobby,
like something I do outside work.
And so I have this picture of me
just having flown that airplane to be like,
"Look, I can do things other than being a nerd."
But in fact, I am a big old nerd.
Most of what I do in my spare time
is more working with LLMs.
And I'm honestly really bad at anything else.
So you're lucky.
You're lucky that this is how we get to work together,
because this is all I'm good at.
And as it turns out, when I flew that plane,
I was really bad at it.
And so if you get on a plane and you
see that it's me there behind the stick,
you want to be looking for a parachute really quickly.
You ought to be getting out of there.
But if you find yourself on a course and I'm there and I'm teaching about
LLMs, then congratulations.
You've come to the right place.
That's what I'm good at.
And that brings me to the other thing I do, which is explaining
LLMs and agents to other people.
I speak at conferences and live events.
And of course, I teach a bunch of courses on Udemy.
It's been my great joy, but I have more than 400,000 people on
my various different courses and I absolutely love it and I'm very good at interacting with
people. If you send me a message, I will reply and it's not an agent, it's really me.
Try me and I'll reply right away. I very much enjoy interacting with people and I love the whole
process of explaining things and I can't wait to be doing that with you
over the next three weeks.
So as I say, I have five other courses on Udemy,
and you might be wondering,
how exactly does this fit in with the other things I do?
I've got a course that's called AI Builder
that is about building solutions,
using platforms like N8N and 11 Labs,
Agents and Voice Agents.
I've got three different courses for AI
engineers. There's a core track and a genetic track and an MLOps track.
And then I have a leadership course, a briefing for business leaders and
for tech people too, on what it takes to build a durable AI business and
deliver AI to production and building a roadmap to deliver commercial impact.
building a roadmap to deliver commercial impact. And so this is my latest course.
This is AI CODA.
This is for people who want to write code using AI and agents to help them.
Now, all of these courses,
I often get the question of which order should I take your courses?
And I always say, look,
I've built these courses to be complementary.
If there is overlap and it's only additive. It makes absolute sense to
take them in whatever order works best for you. If you're looking for an order to take them in,
then I do have a webpage on my homepage called Curriculum, which lays out the curriculum,
explains how they relate to each other, and perhaps the most natural order to take them in.
And it's always possible that I've made more courses since I've spoken to you now, in which case you'll find those other
courses also explained on my curriculum page and laid out so that you can connect the dots
between them. But this course that you're on right now is a bit of an odd one out. And let me
tell you what I mean by that. Most of the courses that I teach, if not all the courses I teach,
are about how do you use technology? How do you write code in order to make AI platforms,
AI products or AI agents?
So it's about using code to make agents.
This course is kind of the other way round.
This is about using agents to write code.
And that code can also itself be about new AI products.
So it's certainly worth having this in mind
that most of my courses are about people who want to build AI
How do you write code to build AI?
And this is about how do you use AI in order to write code?
And there's something circular going on there, which is confusing, but hopefully that's clear to you and you understand what I mean
That's why this course is a bit different to all of the others, although it's still very complementary to everything else
And now I've had a particular strategy when putting together
this course curriculum for AI CODA. And that is that I've tried to combine both breadth and depth.
I've tried to think about covering this whole space quite broadly, but also going deep on what
I think is most interesting and important. So in terms of breadth, I wanted to make sure that we
touch on a large number of different kinds of tools that you may encounter in different
jobs and different environments or working with others. Now, one of these might be your
favorite. It might become your go to, but I certainly want to make sure that you've had exposure
to lots of them. It doesn't mean that you need to pay for them, that you could just watch me,
or there's free trials of most of these, but certainly I'd like you to have that exposure,
so you feel comfortable knowing about all these different tools out there,
at least the most popular ones. But I do want to go deep on one front. I want to go deep on
CLI coding in Cloud Code or also potentially in Open Code or others that are similar. So that
is how we will go deep and in weeks two and three we're going to go much deeper on that front.
So I want to leave you with both the breadth and the depth, combine them both for
this course. And that's a nice segue to laying out the three-week program that I have in store for
you. And this, this is the curriculum construct that we will come back to lots of times. I'm going
to show you that there's going to be three types of session. There's going to be ones where we focus
on core skills. There's going to be ones where we talk about actual platforms, products, things like
codecs and cloud code and cursor. And then there's going to be real commercial projects.
Aside from today, which doesn't count, they're going to be real commercial projects all the way
through. So these are the three different types of session that we will have.
And with that, I have divided your learning into three weeks. Week one, I'm calling it vibe coding for fun and profit. Week one is going to be about
vibe coding. Week two is using a new term that's kind of coming up that was sort of coined by
by an amazing writer, Simon Wilson, vibe engineering, which is more about being a pro, going beyond vibe coding into using this tooling for more professional purposes.
And then week three is a genetic engineering as an expert. This is where you are, you are really
at the sort of top of what is possible, what is capable, using the best of this technology.
And on each of these weeks, I have got five days worth of material. Everything is divided into five days
within each of the three weeks.
You get two days off.
And you can see how I've laid it out here
for the first week.
We are today in day one,
which is that box on the bottom left,
the agentic coding landscape.
That's where we are right now.
And then during the course of this week,
we'll have another purple day on core skills
about the foundation's agents, context,
the tool tomorrow.
Then we're going to have a yellow day
when we look at the different tooling, cursor,
copilot, codecs, anti-gravity.
And then we're going to have two projects.
The first project I'm calling YOLO
and the second project is a commercial MVP.
We'll be doing all of that this week,
week one, vibe coding for fun and profit.
And then next week, vibe engineering,
we go deep into CLI code.
We're going to be using Cloud Code and Open Code
and some others.
We're going to look at commands and checkpoints.
They think of Ralph Loops, which is what I just
demod you the result of.
We're going to be then looking at MCP, Skills, plugins,
which is going to be really interesting material.
And definitely the stuff that people are debating
feverishly at the moment. We're going to look at building workflows, working with a team, debugging
when you're trying to debug existing problems or debugging problems that your AI agent has built,
and then we'll have a really meaty project at the end of the week, a SaaS platform that we will
build together, will be us together and also with our AI agents.
And everything will culminate in week three,
which is really when we raise the bar,
we start with multi-agents running with lots of agents
and sub-agents and using hooks.
We'll spend a whole day digging into sandboxing,
perhaps with some other advanced things
thrown in there too, such an important topic.
Then we will work on large code bases.
This is certainly where you start to see rough edges with Agentic AI.
And we'll figure out what is the survival guide for working with a large code base.
Then really fun topics of agents, swarms and orchestrators of all the rage and we will finally end with a super juicy capstone project, a fitting
finale for this three week curriculum. And at the end of it, you'll be able to say,
yes, I am now an expert, a genetic engineer. You'll be able to respond to Andre's tweet and say,
I've got the missing manual and you'll be able to build large scale, high quality software with a team of agents working for you.